tutor2u.net 2019-10-09

# Privacy Policy | tutor2u

Effective from 25th May 2018

This privacy policy explains how we collect, use, share and transfer your personal data when you use the services provided on tutor2u.net (“our website”).  

## Who we are

Tutor2u Limited is the data controller of your personal data. When we mention “tutor2u”, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy policy, we mean Tutor2u Limited, 214 High Street, Boston Spa, West Yorkshire, LS23 6AD (registered company number 04489574).

Back to top

## What we mean by personal data

**Personal data**  is any information about you, alone or together with other information, by which you can be identified. Examples include:  

  * Your name, email address, postal address, phone number, mobile number
  * Information about your device (such as the IP address, which is a numerical code to identify your device that can provide information about the country, region or city where you are based)
  * Information about your personal circumstances and how you use our website, such as your educational status (e.g.teacher, student, parent) or employment (e.g. a teaching position at a school, or a finance department)

Back to top

## How we collect personal data

Most of the personal data we collect is **provided to us directly by you** for one of the following reasons:

  * You register for a tutor2u account on our website
  * You update your account settings or preferences
  * You purchase any of our products or services
  * You attend one of our events
  * You reply to one of our competitions or surveys
  * You sign up for marketing communications
  * You contact our customer support team

We also **receive personal data indirectly** , in the following scenarios:

  * When you browse our website, we use common internet technologies to automatically record information about your interactions. Please refer to our use of cookies and tracking for more information on this.
  * Your personal data may sometimes be **provided on your behalf** , either by a colleague, family member or someone who knows you well. For example, when you ask a colleague or parent to book your place on one of our events.

Back to top

## Why we use your personal data

We use personal data collected through our website for a number of purposes, including the following:  

  * To provide the services you sign up for, such as fulfilling orders, running events, and delivering premium content.
  * To send you service-related notices, notifications of website activity relating to your account, product and service announcements and changes to features of the website.
  * To personalise our services (for example, so you can sign in), remembering your settings, displaying personalised content and recommendations, recognising you when you sign in on different devices and tailoring our marketing communications based on what you read on our websites.
  * To carry out marketing analysis, for example we look at what you have viewed on our website and what products and services you have bought (including what you have looked at) to better understand what your interests and preferences are, and to improve our marketing by making it more relevant to your interests and preferences.
  * To improve our marketing communications and determine the effectiveness of promotional campaigns and advertising.
  * To provide customer support and respond to your queries.
  * For statistical purposes such as analysing the performance of our website and to understand how visitors use them.
  * For security and fraud prevention, and to ensure that our website is safe and secure and used in line with our terms of use.
  * To comply with applicable laws, regulations, and industry standards.

Back to top

## Legal grounds for using your personal data

We will only use your personal data where we have a legal ground to do so. We determine the legal grounds based on the purposes for which we have collected and used your personal data. In every case, the legal ground will be one of the following:

  * **Consent**  from you **.**  For example, where you have provided your consent to receive marketing emails from us. You can withdraw your consent at any time. In the case of marketing emails you can withdraw your consent by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the email or through your email preferences, when signed into your tutor2u account.
  *  **Our legitimate interests**.  Where it is necessary for us to understand our customers, improve our services and communications, and operate our website efficiently and securely, for the benefit of customers and website users. For example, we will rely on our legitimate interest when we analyse what content has been viewed on our website, so that we can understand how it is used. It is also in our legitimate interest to carry out marketing analysis to determine what products and services may be relevant to the interests of our customers.
  *  **Performance of a contract**  with you, or in order to take steps prior to entering into a contract with you. For example, where you have purchased a product from us and we need to use your contact details and payment information in order to process and fulfil your order.
  *  **Compliance with law**. In some cases, we may have a legal obligation to use or keep your personal data.

Back to top

## How we share the data we collect

We  **do**  share personal data with your permission, so we can perform services you have requested or communicate on your behalf. For example, if you request our 'Invoice my school' payment option, we may share your name, email address and position when we contact the school to seek authorisation.

We  **do**  share personal data with a limited number of third party vendors and service providers who process it on our behalf to provide or improve our service. Our vendors perform services such as payment processing, customer support ticketing, network data transmission, statistical analysis, and other similar services. 

We may share your personal data with third-parties under the following circumstances:

  * We are compelled to do so to meet a legal or regulatory obligation, or otherwise to protect our rights or the rights of anyone else.
  * We are involved in a merger, sale, or acquisition. If this happened, we would use reasonable efforts to try to make sure that the organisation we transfer your personal data to uses it in line with our privacy policy.

We  **do not**  share, sell, rent, or trade personal data with any third-parties for their own marketing or commercial purposes, except where you have specifically told us to.

Back to top

## Using children’s personal data

We do not aim any of our products or services directly at children under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect personal data about children under 13.

Back to top

## Security of your personal data

We have implemented appropriate technical and organisational controls to protect your personal data against unauthorised processing and against accidental loss, damage or destruction.   

You are responsible for choosing a secure password when we ask you to set up a password to access parts of our website. You should keep this password confidential and you should choose a password that you do not use on any other site. You should not share your password with anyone else, including anyone who works for us. 

Unfortunately, sending information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data once with us, we cannot guarantee the security of any personal data sent to our site while still in transit and so you provide it at your own risk.

Back to top

## International data transfers

As part of the services offered to you through our website, the information which you give to us may be transferred to countries out of the European Economic Area (EEA).  

For example, some of our third-party providers (such as our web server hosts and cloud-storage hosts) may be located outside of the EEA. Where this is the case we will take steps to make sure the right security measures are taken so that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this policy. By submitting your personal data, you’re agreeing to this transfer, storing or processing. 

Where our third-party providers are in the United States (US) we have ensured that their services fall under the "Privacy Shield" whereby participating companies are deemed to have adequate protection and therefore facilitate the transfer of information from the EEA to the US.

If you use our services while you are outside the EEA, your information may be transferred outside the EEA to give you those services.

Back to top

## How long we keep your personal data

We keep your personal data for as long as we need it for the purposes for which it was collected.

When we decide how long we will keep your information we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure, why we need it, and any relevant legal requirements.

We may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes, in which case we may use this information indefinitely.

When you unsubscribe from marketing communications, we will keep your email address to ensure that we do not send you any marketing in future.  

Back to top

## Email communications

We may send you service emails, for example, when you create an account, reminding you of an upcoming event you're attending, or confirming an order you've placed. You may not opt out of these emails.

Periodically, we may also send you other product updates and announcements by email. If you do not want to receive such email messages, you may opt out or change your preferences when you are signed in to your tutor2u account.

We also offer a range of other email alerts and subject-specific newsletters. Again, you can manage your subscription to these emails when you are signed in to your tutor2u account.

Back to top

## Our use of cookies and tracking

Cookies are small data files that are placed on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. Cookies are widely used by website owners in order to make their websites work, or to work more efficiently, as well as to provide reporting information.

We refer to cookies created by us as "first party cookies". We refer to cookies that we set on our website but that are created by parties other than us as "third party cookies". Third party cookies enable third party features or functionality to be provided on or through the website (e.g. like advertising, interactive content and analytics). The parties that provide these third party cookies can recognise your computer both when it visits the website in question and also when it visits certain other websites.

A “web beacon”, also known as a tag, pixel tag, or clear GIF, is used to transmit information back to a web server. When we talk about “cookies” in this privacy notice, we mean not just cookies, but web beacons and similar technologies.

### Why we use cookies

We use both first and third party cookies for several reasons. The broad categories of first and third party cookies in use on our website are:

  * **Essential website cookies:**  These cookies are strictly necessary to provide you with services available through our website and to use some of its features, such as access to restricted content. Refusal of these cookies may impact website functionality.
  *  **Performance and functionality cookies:**  These cookies are used to enhance the performance and functionality of our website but are non-essential to their use. However, without these cookies, certain functionality may become unavailable.
  *  **Analytics and customisation cookies:**  These cookies collect information that is used either in aggregate form to help us understand how our website is being used or how effective our marketing campaigns are, or to help us customise our website for you.
  *  **Advertising cookies:**  These cookies are used to make advertising messages more relevant to you. They perform functions like preventing the same ad from continuously re-appearing, ensuring that ads are properly displayed for advertisers, and in some cases selecting advertisements that are based on your interests.
  *  **Social networking cookies:**  These cookies are used to enable you to share pages and content that you find interesting on our website through third party social networking and other websites. These cookies may also be used for advertising purposes too.

By using our website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your computer or device. If you disable your browser or device’s ability to accept cookies, you may not be able to use the features of our website to their fullest potential.

Back to top

## Your rights to data access and control

You can contact us with regard to the following rights in relation to your personal data:

  * You would like to have a copy of the personal data we hold on you or if you think that we hold incorrect personal data about you. We will deal with requests for copies of your personal data or for correction of your personal data within one month. If your request is complicated or if you have made a large number of requests, it may take us longer. We will let you know if we need longer than one month to respond. You will not have to pay a fee to obtain a copy of your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive.
  * Where applicable, you may also have a right to receive a machine-readable copy of your personal data for easier portability.
  * You also have the right to ask us to delete your personal data or restrict how it is used. There may be exceptions to the right to erasure for specific legal reasons which, if applicable, we will set out for you in response to your request. Where applicable, you have the right to object to processing of your personal data for certain purposes.

If you want to make any of these requests, please email [privacy@tutor2u.net](mailto:privacy@tutor2u.net) or write to Fiona Harris (Data Protection Officer) at Tutor2u Limited, 214 High Street, Boston Spa, West Yorkshire, LS23 6AD.

Back to top

## How to contact us

If you have any questions or concerns about how we use your personal data, please contact Fiona Harris (Data Protection Officer) at Tutor2u Limited, 214 High Street, Boston Spa, West Yorkshire, LS23 6AD. Or email [privacy@tutor2u.net](mailto:privacy@tutor2u.net).

If you are not satisfied with how your concern has been handled, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the relevant supervisory authority. The supervisory authority in the UK is the Information Commissioner’s Office.

If you have a question about anything else, please [contact our support team](https://www.tutor2u.net/contact).

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy we will post the changes here. If the changes are significant, we may also choose to email all our registered users with the new details. 

Back to top
